# **Omar Rodriguez Soberanes**

Developer

**Location**: Guadalajara Jalisco Mexico

Phone: 6621-393007 omar.rodsob@gmail.com

## **Summary**

I'm a self-motivated front end developer with more than 10 years of experience and start with QA automation and integration testing since 2020, working with cross functional teams, working in agile environments more than 6 years, passionate for the front end technologies, on web browser and mobile, keep focus on both personal and team growth, working in close collaboration with business, designers and back end developers.

### **Experience**

HCL, Guadalajara Jalisco — QA

September 2017 to May 2023

- Working usaa has a contractor.
- Working in the migration from readyapi to postman for several projects to have the integration testing on the pipelines for gitlab.
- Working on the integration of cypress for 3 projects to apply the test automation.
- Working on several migrations, migrating projects from ocp3 to ocp4, migrating ui projects from ocp3 to aws, the focus was in some cases the creation of new tests and monitoring of those already programmed of testing, manual, automated(cypress) and integration(postman).
- Working in the design, code, and implementation of the test cases with cypress and postman, for their implementation and use, both locally and in the different gitlab stages connected to Qtest via integration and ui test pipeline.
- Experience using, postman, cypress, react, gitlab, understanding of ci/cd, agile methodologies, jira, qtest, apiportal.
- Understanding gitlab.yml, webpack, package.json, cypress.config.js configurations.
- Working in my free time in the understanding and practice of webdrive.io and playwright and appium.

# **Korsoftocorp,** Hermosillo sonora — Front End Lead

October 2013 to August 2017.

- Support the team with the activities related to the front-end team, taking the duties to resolve both technical and business problems.
- Maintaining communication with the business owners and translating the specifications to at a technical level.
- Helping manage the releases of the applications in the AppStore and playstore, making sure that we are on date with the requirements from bot platforms.
- We launched 3 hybrid apps, one in Córdoba and two in react native, in addition to this, we maintain a fourth that was build in appcelerator.
- The main tools that we use in these projects are Córdova, ionic, AppStore, playstore, GitHub, postman, react and redux.
- Develop an app for the management of soccer football coaches taking control of the teams, games schedules, players organization, and maintain communication with parents, was made in the first instance in Córdoba with ionic, and PHP on the back end side working with rest APIs maintained on aws cloud servers.
- Another app was to keep control of the maintenance activities for a college, keeping track of tasks on all floors, scheduled new activities, assigning duties, and track the activities by status, we have an admin portal built in php and one app on ios where the workers can see his activities, change the status.

#### **Internet Brands**, Guadalajara jalisco — Front End Lead

February 2012 to October 2013.

- Development and maintenance of various pages of the company as <a href="www.carsdirect.com">www.carsdirect.com</a>, develop the content delivery application for the hosting.
- Started in the planning and development of <a href="https://www.davesgarden.com/showcase">www.davesgarden.com/showcase</a>, from the scratch.
- We provide an image content management system, working closely with business, designers and backend.
- Organize and check the work of four more frontend devs, code reviews and help in solutions to the problems.
- Analyze the use of different tools like bootstrap, angular, jquerymobile to conclude which is best suited to the project or if it is better has our own front end architecture.

## **Quepasa.com,** Hermosillo sonora — Front End Lead

October 2007 to January 2012.

- Facilitate an environment where my team is able to share ideas and perform their best by promoting communication, removing roadblocks, listening to feedback on issues, etc.
- Maintaining communication with the business owners, designers and translating the specifications to at a technical level.
- Coordinated the schedule from front end team, verify the work meets with web standards like w3c

standard, user interface, user experience and web usability, seo,

- Make troubleshooting test, and formal testing and
- Research about new technologies or tools for the sake of our projects, web analytics.
- Helping the front end team to grow in every level, focus on his technical skills and communication, we grow from 3 members to 9 in 3 years.

#### **Education**

**College**: Instituto Tecnológico de Hermosillo.

Career: Licenciatura en Informática(college degree).

Profile

+ 12 years as front end developer

+ 2 years working with the quality assurance stage of software development and deployment.

**CSM**: Certified Scrum Master by scrum alliance with certificate.

#### **Skills**

**Primary skills**: Front end developer, Automation Tester.

**Secondary skills**: Usability testing, troubleshooting test, Analyst Information, User experience, testing (quality control), web analytics.

**Programming Tools**: javascript, cypress, postman, webdriveio, playwright ,react, react native, redux, lint, enzyme, npm, css, jquery, html, html5, node.js, ,app mobile delivery, html for mobile sites (responsive html), rest, web service, json, bootstrap, couchdb, dom manipulation php, laravel, cordova, phonegap, titanium, hockeyapp, testflight, itunes connect, mysql workbrench, moodle, smarty, velocity.

**Others**: Atlassian tools like jira or confluence, MS Project, MS Office, Visio, scrum techniques, trac, cvs, svn, git, windows,linux,macos,android and ios.

.